SIMONE SCHNEEBERG

(917) 828 5437 simone.m.schneeberg@gmail.com github.com/sschneeberg www.sschneeberg.com Washington, DC

Early career full stack developer with an adept problem solving ability, garnered from a mixed background of creative arts and engineering. More than one year of experience in project management, team leadership, and coordination.

SKILLS

Languages: Javascript/Node.js, CSS, HTML5, Python | Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB | Testing: Mocha, Chai, Supertest | Libraries + Frameworks: Express, React, React Native, Django, Flask, Bootstrap, Sequelize, Mongoose, Socket.io | Tools: Trello, Salesforce, Quickbooks, Zapier, Slack, Github, Heroku, MongoDB Atlas | Methodologies: REST, OOP, MVC, User Stories, Responsive Design, Agile | Other: Welding, Carpentry, Rapid Prototyping, CAD/CAE

RECENT PROJECTS

TierBreaker, Flask/React Application

anuary 2021

- Designed database models and created a fully tested Flask API with Socket.io integration as Backend Engineer
- Supported frontend team through thoughtful api design, Created React components and CSS stylesheets as needed
- Taught myself Flask, MongoEngine, and Python Socketio to create a full stack application in less than one week

Pest Damage Report (A Bug Tracking Application), MERN Stack Web Application

December 2020

- Lead team of four to create full stack application in ten days, Maintained group repository and development schedule
- Spearheaded back end api and database development in Express with MongoDB, Implemented Socket.io functionality
- Instated user authentication with tiered permissions to allow multifunctional use of the app with varied api access

Tracker App, Express Web Application/React Native Application

December 2020/Ongoing

- Collaborating with UX designers to create a gender neutral period tracker with focus on user designated priorities
- Currently iterating front and backend structure to transition to market research backed features in a mobile application
- Managed an eight model relational database, implementing both the Sequelize ORM and raw SQL queries
- Organized project into controllers, views, and specialized middleware to maintain DRY and MVC strategies

RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Remote

Oct 2020 - Present

Software Engineering Fellow

- Tackled daily MVP assignments, covering full stack development of web applications
- Completed and deployed four, week-long projects involving the ideation and creation of web apps from scratch
- Aided other cohort members with the understanding of new concepts, engaged in self lead learning outside of classes

SKA Custom Robots and Machines, Washington, DC

July 2020 - Present

Senior Coordinator

- Mobilized stalled website development within one week as acting project manager working with a contractor
- Slashed time spent on project tracking by 50% through implementing Salesforce to Quickbooks Integrations
- Initialized new strategies for networking and increasing sales in the newly virtual landscape of industry events

Studio Theatre, Washington, DC

July 2019 - June 2020

Assistant Technical Director/Apprentice

- Trimmed costs to fit within \$6000 budget by ideating alternatives without sacrificing any design elements
- Engineered and drafted technical drawings optimized for efficient use of construction time and materials
- Collaborated across departments and worked closely with designers to ensure full execution of creative vision

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University, Carnegie Institute of Technology, Pittsburgh, PA

May 2019

BS, Mechanical Engineering with University Honors

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive (Remote), Washington, DC

January 2021